<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Publications on My Computational Genomic Playground</title><link>https://zqfang.github.io/publication/</link><description>Recent content in Publications on My Computational Genomic Playground</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zqfang.github.io/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SOX21 Ensures Rostral Forebrain Identity by Suppression of WNT8B during Neural Regionalization of Human Embryonic Stem Cells</title><link>https://zqfang.github.io/publication/2019-12-10-sox21/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zqfang.github.io/publication/2019-12-10-sox21/</guid><description>My PhD thesis. Published in Stem Cell Reports, 2019
Highlights
The transcriptomic analysis of rostrocaudal patterning of hESC-derived NPCs SOX21 KO leads to caudalized regional identity in rostral forebrain progenitors SOX21 represses Wnt signaling to ensure the rostral forebrain identity WNT8B is a major downstream target of SOX21 Download here</description></item><item><title>CDK11 safeguards the identity of human embryonic stem cells via fine‐tuning signaling pathways</title><link>https://zqfang.github.io/publication/2019-10-15/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zqfang.github.io/publication/2019-10-15/</guid><description>Ding J, Fang Z, Liu X, Zhu Z, Wen C, Wang H, et al. CDK11 safeguards the identity of human embryonic stem cells via fine-tuning signaling pathways. J Cell Physiol. 2019
Download here</description></item><item><title>Stk40 deletion elevates c-JUN protein level and impairs mesoderm differentiation</title><link>https://zqfang.github.io/publication/2019-06-21/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zqfang.github.io/publication/2019-06-21/</guid><description>Hu J, Li S, Sun X, Fang Z, Wang L, Xiao F, et al. Stk40 deletion elevates c-JUN protein level and impairs mesoderm differentiation. J Biol Chem. 2019;294(25):9959-72.
Download here</description></item><item><title>Transcription coactivator Cited1 acts as an inducer of trophoblast-like state from mouse embryonic stem cells through the activation of BMP signaling</title><link>https://zqfang.github.io/publication/2018-09-11/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zqfang.github.io/publication/2018-09-11/</guid><description>Xu Y, Luo X, Fang Z, Zheng X, Zeng Y, Zhu C, et al. Transcription coactivator Cited1 acts as an inducer of trophoblast-like state from mouse embryonic stem cells through the activation of BMP signaling. Cell Death Dis. 2018;9(9):924.
Download here</description></item><item><title>Bioconda: sustainable and comprehensive software distribution for the life sciences</title><link>https://zqfang.github.io/publication/2018-07-02/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zqfang.github.io/publication/2018-07-02/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m honored to be one of the contributors. It is definitely worthy. Thanks for the Bioconda team, so we could install bioinformatic tools so easy! The open source Bioconda project is a milestone in computational biology. It saves lots of time when trying to install bioinfo tools.
Download here</description></item><item><title>Single-cell analysis reveals lineage segregation in early post-implantation mouse embryos</title><link>https://zqfang.github.io/publication/2016-06-09/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zqfang.github.io/publication/2016-06-09/</guid><description>Wen J, Zeng Y, Fang Z, Gu J, Ge L, et al. Single-cell analysis reveals lineage segregation in early post-implantation mouse embryos. The Journal of biological chemistry 2017;292:9840-54
Download here</description></item><item><title>Deletion of Stk40 impairs definitive erythropoiesis in the mouse fetal liver</title><link>https://zqfang.github.io/publication/2017-03-30/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zqfang.github.io/publication/2017-03-30/</guid><description>Wang L, Yu H, Cheng H, He K, Fang Z, et al. Deletion of Stk40 impairs definitive erythropoiesis in the mouse fetal liver. Cell Death Dis. 2017;8:e2722
Download here</description></item><item><title>Itch, an E3 ligase of Oct4, is required for embryonic stem cell self-renewal and pluripotency induction</title><link>https://zqfang.github.io/publication/2012-12-18/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zqfang.github.io/publication/2012-12-18/</guid><description>Liao B, Zhong XM, Xu HM, Xiao F, Fang ZQ, et al. Itch, an E3 ligase of Oct4, is required for embryonic stem cell self-renewal and pluripotency induction. Journal of Cellular Physiology 2013;228:1443-51
Download here</description></item></channel></rss>